<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>An Nguyen</title><link>https://davidnguyen58.github.io/An_Blog/</link><description>Recent content on An Nguyen</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.155.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:26:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidnguyen58.github.io/An_Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TCP vs UDP</title><link>https://davidnguyen58.github.io/An_Blog/posts/blog2_udp_tcp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:26:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidnguyen58.github.io/An_Blog/posts/blog2_udp_tcp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;UDP and TCP two main protocols in the Transport Layer of the OSI and TCP/IP models. Both protocols help applications to communicate with each other, however, they are different mainly in terms of speed, reliability and use cases. We will explore the basic ideas behind each protocol and their use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="user-datagram-protocol"&gt;User Datagram Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The User Datagram Protocol (UDP) is an efficient communication protocol which allows fast transmission of data packet at the cost of reliability. The protocol works by sending packets directly to the target computer without setting up the connection. It&amp;rsquo;s worth to note that the UDP protocol does not guarantee packet delivery, and the ordering of the packets.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Universal Approximation Theorem</title><link>https://davidnguyen58.github.io/An_Blog/posts/blog1_uat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:13:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidnguyen58.github.io/An_Blog/posts/blog1_uat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first learnt about Deep Learning, I was always wondering how can these neural networks can perform a wide range of complex tasks. The idea of defining an objective function and then train the neural networks to minimise that seems intuitive to understand about the mechanism but does not justify why it would work. It turns out that when I came across the Universal Approximation Theorem, things get clearer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>